Finding Aid for Sylvan Township, Washtenaw County, Mich. records, 1834-1925
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Sylvan Township, Washtenaw County, Mich. records 1834-1925
Sylvan (Washtenaw County, Mich.: Township).
2.5 linear feet and 3 oversize volumes
86222 Cb.2/2
Sylvan Township, Washtenaw County, Michigan records.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group is an amalgam of records from different donors. The bulk of the records came from Fred Hoffman (donor no. 10117 ) in 2008; one township record book was donated by Louis Doll (donor no. 1338 ) in 1985; and the school records were donated by Edna R. Faulkner (donor no. 3024 ) in 1953.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
Sylvan Township is located in western Washtenaw County. Chelsea is the largest city in the Township.
The record group consists of township board records, 1834-1910, justice of the peace docket books, 1885-1925, assessment books, 1859-1886 (with some gaps), minutes of the board of school inspectors, 1866-1894, and records of School District Number 7 records, 1837-1910.
Subjects:
Education--Michigan--Sylvan (Washtenaw County: Township); Elections--Michigan--Sylvan (Washtenaw County: Township); Roads--Michigan--Sylvan (Washtenaw County: Township); School census--Michigan--Sylvan (Washtenaw County: Township); Schools--Michigan--Sylvan (Washtenaw County: Township); Washtenaw County (Mich.); Taxation--Michigan--Sylvan (Washtenaw County: Township); Sylvan (Washtenaw County, Mich.: Township)
- Township Board
  - Poll list: statements of votes and other records, 1834-1853 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of the township board, 1863-1882, original and photocopy (Box 1)
  - Township record book, 1882-1892 (Box 1)
    (include minutes of meetings, etc.)
  - Township record book, 1905-1911 (Box 1)
  - Combined volume: include records of drain commission, 1891-1895 and highway commissioner, 1893-1895 (Box 1)
  - Town Book for Accounts and Mortgages, 1835-1867 and 1851-1882 (Volume 1)
    (volume was used for multiple purposes)
- Justice of the Peace Docket Books and related
  - Civil cases, 1885-1886 (Box 2)
  - Civil cases, 1893-1925 (Box 2)
  - Criminal cases, 1885-1903 (Box 2)
  - Litigation: Retirement Homes of the Detroit Annual Conference of the United Methodist Church v. Sylvan Township (Respondent-Appellant's Brief on Appeal; Respondent-Appellant Appendix), 1980 (Box 2)
- Assessment Books
  - 1859 (Box 2)
  - 1862 (Box 2)
  - 1866 (Box 2)
  - 1867 (Box 2)
  - 1868 (Volume 2)
  - 1886 (Volume 3)
- Schools
  - Minutes of the board of school inspectors, 1866-1894 (Box 3)
  - School District Number 7 records
    - Minutes of the board, 1837-1868 (Box 3)
      (includes minutes of the board of School District No. 1, 1834-1837)
    - School district record book: includes Minutes of the board, 1865-1910; Register of officers, 1865-1905; Teacher contracts, 1865-1891; Register of teachers, 1866-1884; Expense record, 1865-1910; School census, 1877-1910; Financial report, 1889-1903 (Box 3)
    - School forms book: includes Acceptance of office, 1896-1900; Assessor's bond, 1896; Teacher contracts, 1896-1909; Receipts, 1897-1910 (Box 3)
    - Teacher's daily register, 1899-1900 (Box 3)
    - Lease for school property, 1842 (Box 3)